BRUCE: There was a time above.
A time before.
There were perfect things,
diamond absolutes.
How things fall.
Things on Earth.
- And what falls...
- (WIND HOWLING)
ALFRED: (SOFTLY) Master Wayne!
- ...is fallen.
- Bruce!
(PANTING)
Bruce, it's all right.
Bruce, please.
(BRUCE CONTINUES PANTING)
(GUN COCKING)
(GROANS)
(GROANING)
(GUN FIRES)
(SCREAMING INAUDIBLY)
(GASPING)
Martha.
(GROANING)
(WINGS FLAPPING)
(BATS SQUEAKING)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(BATS SQUEAKING LOUDLY)
(GASPING)
(SCREECHING)
(GRUNTING)
BRUCE: In the dream,
they took me to the light.
A beautiful lie.
(TIRES SCREECHING)
(ENGINE ROARING)
(SIRENS WAILING)
- Jack.
- Bruce.
Jack, listen to me.
I want you to get everyone
out of the building right now.
- You understand?
- Oh, my God.
- WOMAN: Stay away from the windows!
- (SHOUTING)
Let's go. Come on.
Start moving now, people. Let's go.
The boss wants us out of the building,
so let's make it happen.
Jack. Jack!
(TIRES SCREECHING)
(CAR ALARMS BLARING)
(JACK GASPS)
- (INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS)
- (PANTING)
- (CELL PHONE BEEPS)
- OPERATOR: We're sorry.
All circuits are busy now.
Will you please try your call again later?
Heavenly God,
creator of Heaven and Earth,
have mercy on my soul.
- (PANICKED SHOUTING)
- (BRUCE GASPS)
Jack!
Buddy hands! Everybody show me! Good job!
Come on, guys.
Hold on tight.
- (WHIMPERS)
- Go.
WALLACE: Mr. Wayne!
Mr. Wayne! I can't feel my legs.
- (GRUNTS)
- I can't feel my legs.
- We need help over here!
- (BREATHING HEAVILY)
Help me. I can't feel my legs.
You're gonna be okay. You hear me?
Wallace?
What do they call you, Wally? Huh?
You're the boss, boss.
All right. You're gonna be okay.
Easy, easy. Come on.
(WALLACE GROANING)
Oh, my God. I can't move my leg.
My God. I can't feel my legs.
(GRUNTS) It's okay.
You're gonna be okay.
- You're okay. All right? Huh?
- (SIRENS WAILING)
You know what? We're gonna find your mom.
Where is she?
(SONIC BOOM)
(INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS)
All that wind is bad luck.
Blood in the sky.
Oh, there she is!
Miss Lane.
Miss Lane. Jimmy Olsen.
Photographer. Obviously.
Where's Heron?
Uh, trouble at the border.
So, uh, how'd you land it?
This is, like, pioneer stuff.
Amajagh's never given an interview.
You know what Heron always
says when we're on assignment together?
Not a goddamn thing.
I like Heron.
Let's go.
(SPEAKING OTHER LANGUAGE)
TRANSLATOR: Passports.
Electronics. Phones. Camera.
Your fixer said that
the general approved photos.
(SPEAKING OTHER LANGUAGE)
(LOIS GROANS)
Are you a terrorist, General?
They did not tell me the interview
was with a lady.
I'm not a lady. I'm a journalist.
GENERAL AMAJAGH: What I am
is a man with nothing
except a love of my people.
Who's paying for these
security contractors, General?
Who pays for the drones
that pass over our heads at night?
GENERAL AMAJAGH:
One question begs another.
Yes?
Say what you're saying, General.
It's just a camera.
The United States
has declared its neutrality
in your country's civil war
both in policy and in principle.
Don't open... You just exposed...
(LAUGHING)
These pious American fictions...
...spoken like truth.
Okay. That's my film.
Men with power obey
neither policy nor principle, Miss Lane.
No one is different.
No one is neutral.
(BEEPING)
CIA.
They're tracking us!
You!
(SPEAKING OTHER LANGUAGE)
You're CIA?
What? No. No!
- You brought him here!
- No, he's a photographer.
- No!
- (SPEAKING OTHER LANGUAGE)
It's okay, Lois.
(GUNSHOT ECHOES)
Talon's down, sir.
Python, we have lost our
asset on the ground.
Repeat, we have lost our
PYTHON: There's still a civilian in
the compound. We'll extract her.
Negative. RPA to engage.
Stand down and get black.
There'll be friendlies
in the blast zone, so...
Call off the goddamn drone.
Stand down is an order. Python?
Let's move!
I...
I didn't know.
Ignorance is not the same as innocence,
Miss Lane.
(INDISTINCT CHATTER
IN OTHER LANGUAGE)
(GUNFIRE)
- Get up! Stand up!
- (GASPING)
Quickly. He's coming.
Inbound 2 mikes.
Passing Python now.
(ENGINES REVVING)
Move out!
- PILOT: Target locked.
- You are clear to engage.
PILOT: Armed hot and in range.
- (RAPID BEEPING)
- Three.
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
Two. One.
Link's been hit.
By what?
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
Take one step,
you will see the inside of her head.
(INAUDIBLE SCREAMING)
KAHINA: The women
in the village heard a noise.
Like the sky cracked open.
He came down. Then came fire.
(KAHINA SNIFFLES)
Even worse came after.
The government attacked.
No mercy in the villages.
(SOBS) My parents tried to run.
The world has been so caught up
with what Superman can do
that no one has asked what he should do.
Let the record show that this
committee holds him responsible.
KAHINA: He'll never answer to you.
He answers to no one.
Not even, I think, to God.
ANNOUNCER 1: 58 to nothing.
Metropolis, again,
blowing out Gotham City.
ANNOUNCER 2: Really, only the diehards
are left in the stands.
DISPATCHER: Delta Charlie 27.
Reports of screams coming from vacant home
at 1939 Harborway.
ANNOUNCER 1: Tom, it's been great
working with you.
I want to thank our
producer and director.
- Now wait a second.
- I don't even want to suggest...
DISPATCHER:
Delta Charlie 27, respond.
Just take a knee.
ANNOUNCER 1: They're lining up as if
Clarkson is gonna throw it deep here.
- ANNOUNCER 2: Don't tell me, Dave.
- Going to the end zone!
ANNOUNCER 2: This is unnecessary.
DISPATCHER: Delta Charlie 27.
ANNOUNCER 1: Zeke Baker is open.
Baker with a touchdown catch!
I can't believe I just watched that.
DISPATCHER: Delta Charlie 27.
Do you copy?
10-4. We're on it.
ANNOUNCER 2: And now
a fight breaks out.
Gotham City, you know
how they are about their football team.
Things could get ugly
in the city tonight.
(SIREN WAILING)
(BATS SCREECHING)
(TIRES SCREECHING)
(DOOR CREAKING)
(WHISPERS) Go.
(WOMEN CHATTERING INDISTINCTLY
IN OTHER LANGUAGE)
(SPEAKING OTHER LANGUAGE)
OFFICER RUCKA: It's okay.
It's okay.
(STAMMERS) We're gonna help.
We're here to help.
We're gonna get you out of here. Okay?
(ALL WHIMPERING)
I don't understand.
- (CESAR SCREAMS)
- (WOMEN GASP)
CESAR: Please don't.
Please don't.
Please. I don't know who he is.
I don't know who he is!
(SCREAMING) No!
(CESAR GROANING)
(CONTINUES GROANING)
Oh, fuck.
(GROANING)
Christ!
I saw him.
I never saw him before.
I... I didn't know.
You almost took my face off.
How about you don't shoot
the good guys, huh?
Oh. Oh.
Jesus Christ.
He branded him.
(DOOR CLOSES)
(KNOCKING ON DOOR)
- Hey.
I was gonna cook.
Surprise you.
They held hearings about what happened.
- They're saying that...
- I don't care.
I don't care what they're saying.
The woman I love could have
been blown up or shot.
Think of what could have happened.
Well, think about what did happen.
I didn't kill those men,
if that's what they think.
If that's what you're saying.
No, I'm saying
I want to understand what happened.
I'm saying thank you for saving my life.
I'm saying there's a cost.
I just don't know if it's possible.
Don't know if what's possible?
For you to love me and be you.
(LAUGHS) Clark!
Clark, you're going
to flood the apartment.
- Mmm-hmm.
- (LAUGHING)
BRUCE: You still working?
You're getting slow
in your old age, Alfred.
Comes to us all, Master Wayne.
Even you got too old to die young.
And not for lack of trying.
(IN DEEP VOICE) Funnel-ferry butterbar.
Funnel-ferry butterbar.
Funnel-ferry butterbar. Funnel-ferry...
There's nothing wrong
with the microphone.
It's this new layer of armor.
I'll just have to rewire.
So, last night was productive?
No. He's too low-level. He knew nothing.
This is the man who knows things.
Anatoli Knyazev. He's Russian.
Contracts all over the globe,
but he's based out of the port of Gotham.
Weapons and human trafficking.
ALFRED: So the White Portuguese
is a Russian.
That's the theory.
No. The theory is that the Russian
will lead me to the man himself.
If he is, indeed, a "him."
You don't even know if he exists.
Could be a phantasm.
One that wants to bring
a dirty bomb into Gotham?
Ah, high-stakes round.
ALFRED: New rules.
BRUCE: We're criminals,
Alfred.
We've always been criminals.
Nothing's changed.
Oh, yes, it has, sir.
Everything's changed.
Men fall from the sky.
The gods hurl thunderbolts.
Innocents die.
That's how it starts, sir.
The fever. The rage.
The feeling of powerlessness.
It turns good men cruel.
PLAYER: John, get D.
Ooh. Ah. Ahoy, ahoy!
I did not know you were here.
- Man on the marquee.
- Yeah, don't believe it.
My father named the company
after himself.
He was the Lex in front of the Corp.
How you doin'?
Really great.
Really great? Good. Good.
Uh, follow me.
No, uh, Dad started saying
that he named the company,
after his kid at investor pitches.
Rich old ladies.
They thought it was very cute, you know?
"Write checks for Lex."
You know, Dad was born in East Germany.
He grew up eating stale crackers.
And every other Saturday,
he had to march in a parade
and wave flowers at tyrants.
So, I think it was providence
that his son, me,
would end up with this.
One of my Rebuild Metropolis
crews found it.
Little souvenir from
the Kryptonian World Engine.
What does a rock have to do
with homeland security?
Homeland security? Hmm.
No, no, no, ma'am, planetary security.
The fragment
is of a radioactive xenomineral.
We suspected it might
have bio-interactions,
so we took the sample to AMRIID,
where they keep the remains
of the Kryptonian decedent.
And, when we exposed
General Zod to the mineral,
this happened.
Profound biodegradation.
Decaying Kryptonian cells.
We concluded the mineral
could be weaponized
if a large enough sample was found.
And then, among the fishes, a whale.
Ah!
Lying at the bottom of the Indian Ocean.
Emerald City.
(BREATHES DEEPLY)
Beautiful.
Now, Rocky is radioactive,
but what he needs from you
is an import license.
And why would we want to
weaponize this material?
LEX: As a deterrent.
A silver bullet to keep in reserve,
to use against the Kryptonians,
so the day does not come, madam,
when your children are waving
daisies at a reviewing stand.
Last I looked, the only one of those
flying around up here was Superman.
Ha-ha, yes. Superman.
Yeah, but there are...
There are more of them.
The metahuman thesis.
LEX: Yes, the metahuman thesis.
More likely than not
these exceptional beings live among us.
The basis of our myths.
Gods among men upon
our little blue planet here.
Now, you don't have to use
a silver bullet.
But if you forge one...
(INHALES)
(IN SOUTHERN ACCENT)
Well, then
we don't have to depend
upon the kindness of monsters.
There are ways we can help each other.
(SIGHS) Would you step
into my office here?
Yes.
What's your wish list?
Access to the wreck of
the crashed Kryptonian ship?
Done.
The complete remains
of the dead alien for testing.
(LEX SNIFFLES)
You want Zod's body?
Okay.
- (DOOR OPENS)
- Mmm.
It's cherry.
Mmm-mmm.
KAHINA:
Because the time has come
for the world to hear
the other side of the story.
They say that Superman is a hero.
Okay, but whose hero?
REPORTER: If Superman
were here right now,
what would you want to say to him?
KAHINA: That my family,
too, had dreams.
To look him in his eye
and ask him how he decides
which lives count.
And which ones do not.
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
(GRUNTING)
Sir, get down.
Sir, I said get down!
- Now!
- (ALL GASPING)
COP 2: Can we get some backup here?
Hey! Hey! Don't do it!
Hey!
Lois! Crime lab, on three.
- This is Lane.
- PERRY: Kent.
You're Sports today.
I want you to go to Gotham,
follow up on football.
"Underdog Dreams Dashed:
Ten Yards Between Gotham and Glory."
Watch yourself over there in Gotham.
Don't let them take your lunch money.
Hey. Are you guys watching this?
Emergency responders quickly created
a precautionary perimeter
around Heroes Park
while they brought the man down
from this beloved monument.
The suspect has been identified
as Wallace Vernon Keefe.
I work for Bruce Wayne!
REPORTER: He'll be arraigned
on charges of vandalism,
resisting arrest,
and the felony charge of
making terrorist threats.
That carries up to 40 years in prison.
PERRY: Poor son of a bitch.
REPORTER: Metropolis News 8.
- PERRY: Jenny.
- Hmm.
Headline, "End of Love Affair
with Man in the Sky,
"question mark."
Okay.
(KNOCKING ON DOOR)
(WHISTLING)
Is she in?
No, she's been gone.
POET: What'd she do,
officer?
I'm not a cop. I'm a reporter.
The young lady living here...
She hasn't been back.
In fact, if she's smart,
then she's got out of this city.
And you need to
get out of here before dark.
Unless you want to run into him.
WOMAN: Don't listen to that nonsense.
Only people scared of him,
people who got reason to be.
Scared of who?
There's a new kind of mean in him.
He is angry.
And he's hunting.
- (BOTH GRUNTING)
- (CROWD CHEERING)
WOMAN: Show 'em what you got!
Let's go. Come on!
MAN: Throw a punch,
will ya?
Let's go! Come on!
(CHEERING CONTINUES)
(GRUNTING CONTINUES)
(CROWD APPLAUDING)
(MAN BOOING)
(CORK POPS)
Thank you.
(MAN LAUGHING)
The house treats luck like an insult.
Good luck for one is always
his brother's misfortune.
(BRUCE SPEAKING RUSSIAN)
Three nights with a Bolshoi ballerina,
that line was all she taught me.
Not all, I'm sure. Good evening.
CLARK: It's like a one-man
reign of terror.
This Bat vigilante has been
consistently targeting the port
and the adjacent projects and tenements.
And, as far as I can tell,
the cops are actually helping him.
"Crime Wave in Gotham."
Other breaking news, "Water, Wet."
Did you file the football yet?
Why aren't we covering this?
- Poor people don't buy papers?
- (CHUCKLES)
People don't buy papers, period, Kent.
Perry, when you assign a story,
you're making a choice about who matters.
And who's worth it.
Good morning, Smallville.
The American conscience died
with Robert, Martin, and John.
Sorry. I'm sorry.
No match. My guys in the crime lab
never seen one before.
It's called a bullet.
You shoot people with them.
Recovered from the scene
of the firefight in the desert.
Not sold anywhere
commercially in the world,
even black market.
So?
So who gave prototype military rounds
to Tuareg fighters in the Sahara?
You're the reporter. Tell me.
I think that the US government
is arming the rebels
while claiming to support
the elected government.
The Ask, Lois.
Flight to D.C. tonight.
Couple of days there.
Go.
Coach. No extra legroom.
Economy plus.
Coach!
CLARK: So,
why didn't you tell me?
You're digging up snakes, Lo.
It's kind of dangerous.
That is why I didn't tell you.
PERRY: Lane, don't you
have a plane to catch?
Yes, sir.
Benefit for the Library of Metropolis.
Someone on the committee
requested that Clark Kent cover it.
Probably some old charity crone
who's got a thing for nerds.
LEX: Senator.
Little bourbon before lunch?
My driver's outside. I can't stay.
LEX: No bourbon?
Kentucky girl like yourself?
Hmm.
My dad always said that Kentucky mash
was the secret to health.
(SLURPS) Mmm.
This was his room.
I kept it just the same.
Mmm.
"Maybe one day Dad'll come back
if I just keep everything the same."
(CHUCKLES) That is silly.
The magical thinking of orphan boys.
I'm blocking the import
license for your mineral.
(TAPPING GLASS)
(MOCKING)
The redcapes are coming.
Hmm...
(DRUMMING FINGERS ON TABLE)
You and your hearings.
Galloping through the streets to warn us.
One if by land, two if by air.
- (DRUMMING STOPS)
- Mmm.
Do you know the oldest lie
in America, Senator?
Can I call you June?
You can call me whatever you like.
Take a bucket of piss and
call it Granny's Peach Tea.
Mmm-hmm.
Take a weapon of assassination
and call it deterrence.
You won't fool a fly or me.
I'm not gonna drink it.
You don't think Dad would mind, do you?
If I changed just...
Just one thing in this room?
Because that should be upside-down.
We know better now, don't we?
The devils don't come
from Hell beneath us. No.
No, they come from the sky.
(BLOOD DRIPPING)
(BATS SCREECHING)
(BREATHING SHAKILY)
(SIGHS)
Oh.
I hope the next generation of Waynes
won't inherit an empty wine cellar.
(QUIETLY) Not that there's likely
to be a next generation.
Thank you, sir.
(ALFRED SIGHS)
This is every call made
from the Russian's phone.
Two mentions of business
with the White Portuguese.
And it's continually
transmitting blacked-out data
to the personal residence
of Alexander Luthor.
You think Lex Luthor
is the White Portuguese?
(SNIFFS)
I can't see that he needs the income
from imported arms.
Regardless, I'll need to put
a leech at his house,
and I'm gonna need the suit.
The Bat interrogated six people
and came away with nothing.
It was Bruce Wayne
that got the information.
Well, Bruce Wayne can't
break into Lex Luthor's house.
Bruce Wayne won't have to.
He's been invited.
(REPORTERS CLAMORING)
(CAMERA CLICKING)
Who's that?
You must be new to
the "let them eat cake" beat.
That is Bruce Wayne.
LEBLANC: Philanthropist,
bibliophile...
True friend of the Library of Metropolis.
Mr. Lex Luthor.
- (ALL APPLAUDING)
- Me? Ah. Okay.
Nicky. Uh...
You're embarrassing me.
Um...
Speech, speech. Uh...
Blah, blah, blah. Uh...
Open bar.
(CLEARS THROAT)
The end.
- Uh... (CHUCKLES)
- (GUESTS LAUGHING)
The word "philanthropist"
comes from the Greek.
Meaning a lover of humanity.
It was coined about 2,500 years ago.
All right. Where am I going, Alfred?
Go past the elevator.
Do a left.
That's right, must be.
It's in the service corridor
in the basement.
Go down the stairs.
LEX: Gods and men.
Prometheus went with us.
And he ruined Zeus' plan
to destroy mankind,
and for that he was given a thunderbolt.
(IMITATES THUNDERBOLT ZAPPING)
Hmm, that seems unfair.
On a serious note,
the Library of Metropolis...
Go to the stairs. You saw them
on your way in. Down the stairs.
LEX: But at one time,
Dad could not buy them. No.
My father could not afford
books growing up.
He had to root through the garbage
for yesterday's newspaper.
(TV PLAYING)
All right.
You got the kitchens on your right.
Do a left.
Right in front of you.
That's where you want to be.
May I help you, Mr. Wayne?
I just...
I thought the bathroom was down here.
I must have...
That last martini was
two too many, I think. (CHUCKLES)
Men's room is upstairs.
Great. I'm okay.
I like those shoes.
- (DOOR CLOSES)
- I can't stay down here, Alfred.
ALFRED: Go upstairs
and socialize.
Some young lady from Metropolis
will make you honest.
(SCOFFS) In your dreams, Alfred.
LEX: Books are knowledge,
and knowledge is power,
and I am... (LAUGHS)
No. Uh, um...
No. What am I? I...
What was I saying? No.
The bittersweet pain among men
is having knowledge with
no power, because...
Because that is paradoxical!
And, um... (LAUGHS)
Thank you for coming.
(CLEARS THROAT)
(SCATTERED APPLAUSE)
Please drink. Drink.
(MUSIC PLAYING)
(INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS)
Mr. Wayne? Mr. Wayne?
Clark Kent, Daily Planet.
My foundation has
already issued a statement
in support of books.
- Sir?
- Um...
Wow. Pretty girl. Bad habit.
Don't quote me. All right?
What's your position on
the Bat vigilante in Gotham?
Daily Planet. Do I own this one?
Or is that the other guy?
Civil liberties are being
trampled on in your city.
Good people are living in fear.
Don't believe everything you hear, son.
I've seen it, Mr. Wayne.
He thinks he's above the law.
The Daily Planet criticizing
those who think they're above the law
is a little hypocritical,
wouldn't you say?
Considering every time
your hero saves a cat out of a tree,
you write a puff piece editorial
about an alien who, if he wanted to,
could burn the whole place down.
There wouldn't be a damn thing
we could do to stop him.
Most of the world doesn't
share your opinion, Mr. Wayne.
Maybe it's the Gotham City in me.
We just have a bad history
with freaks dressed like clowns.
LEX: Boys! (CLAPS) Um!
Bruce Wayne meets Clark Kent. Ha!
I love it.
I love bringing people together.
How are we?
- Lex.
- Hello. Good.
Hi, hello, Lex, it is a pleasure.
Wow! That is a good grip!
You should not pick a fight
with this person.
So, after all these years,
we finally got you over to Metropolis.
Well, I thought I'd come drink you dry.
Well, you're welcome.
You should hop the harbor
more often, though.
I'd love to show you my labs.
Maybe we could partner on something.
My R and D is up to all sorts of no good.
That's seven minutes.
Looks like the transfer's complete.
- Mr. Luthor.
- Yes?
- The governor.
- Governor.
- Excuse me.
- Next time.
Governor! Hi!
GOVERNOR:
Lex, it's good to see you.
(REPORTER SPEAKING SPANISH ON TV)
BRUCE: Excuse me.
(INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS)
(ENGINE REVVING)
(SIGHS)
VIKRAM GANDHI: (ON TV)
We, as a population on this planet,
have been looking for a savior.
90% of people believe in a higher power,
and every religion believes
in some sort of messianic figure.
And when this savior character
actually comes to Earth,
we want to make him abide by our rules?
We have to understand that
this a paradigm shift.
We have to start thinking
beyond politics.
ANDREW SULLIVAN: Are there any moral
constraints on this person?
We have international law.
On this Earth,
every act is a political act.
CHARLIE ROSE:
Is it really surprising
that the most powerful man in the world
should be a figure of controversy?
Uh, to have
an individual engaging
in these state-level interventions
should give us all pause.
GLEN WOODBURN: Human beings
have a horrible track record
of following people with great power
down paths that led to
huge human atrocities.
GANDHI: We have always
created icons in our own image.
What we've done is
we project ourselves onto him.
The fact is, maybe he's not
some sort of devil or Jesus character.
Maybe he's just a guy
trying to do the right thing.
NEIL de GRASSE TYSON: We're talking
about a being whose very existence
challenges our own
sense of priority in the universe.
And you go back to Copernicus,
where he restored the Sun
in the center of the known universe,
displacing Earth.
And you get to Darwinian evolution,
and you find out we're not
special on this Earth,
we're just one among other lifeforms.
And now we learn that we're not even
special in the entire universe
because there is Superman.
There he is. An alien among us.
We're not alone.
CHARLIE ROSE: Are you,
as a United States senator,
personally comfortable saying
to a grieving parent,
"Superman could have saved your child,
"but on principle,
we did not want him to act"?
I'm not saying he shouldn't act.
I'm saying he shouldn't act unilaterally.
What are we talking about here, then?
Must there be a Superman?
There is.
(PHONE RINGING)
MARTHA: Hello?
CLARK: Mom?
Clark!
What is it? What's wrong?
No. Nothing. I just...
Hi.
How come Dad never left Kansas?
(SIGHS)
Well, he just...
(CHUCKLING)
You know how he was.
"What do I need to travel for?
"I'm already there."
Just wish it was more simple.
My baby boy.
Nothing was ever simple.
JENET: An odd little duck.
Hmm!
I've never seen a metal like this.
Could be DARPA black box.
Who could find out?
Nobody who'd want to.
Maybe they gave them
out to the rebels to test in theater.
Using live soldiers as guinea pigs?
This is what makes you
such a good reporter.
Stuff like this still shocks you.
(PHONE RINGING)
CESAR: It don't come off!
(CRYING) It don't come off!
COP 1: Prisoner transfer!
You can't put me in general, man.
They gonna kill me.
Hey, you can't bring me to general.
You should be thanking
the tax payers of Metropolis
for taking in your branded ass.
- COP 1: Sign here, please.
- I'm marked, man.
You know what they do
to people with this on them?
- (SPEAKING SPANISH)
- COP 2: He's only a criminal.
- This way! Let's go!
- They're gonna kill me!
- GUARD: Let's go!
Keefe. You made bail.
Open two.
Who paid?
Who the hell are you?
Just a man.
Yeah? Well, what the fuck do you want?
To help you stand for something.
Your three o'clock's here.
He made me half a man.
My wife walked out on me.
I can't even piss standing up.
Let me face him.
You'll take care of it?
Good.
(SIGHS)
What?
(ALARM BLARING)
(INDISTINCT SHOUTING)
Wrong room, miss.
Secretary Swanwick,
you haven't been
returning my phone calls.
Miss Lane, if you'd like an interview,
Major Farris is just outside that door.
You're treating me like a stranger?
I'm treating you like a reporter.
All right. Is the US providing
experimental military arms
to rebels in Africa?
You know, with balls like yours,
you belong in here.
What's your source on this?
A tin foil hat?
No, not tin. But it's metal.
Fired in the Superman incident.
Experts at the Pentagon can't ID it.
We haven't been told the truth.
Here's the truth.
A reporter got greedy for a scoop
and went where she shouldn't have.
Superman acted like some rogue combatant
to rescue her, and people died.
Don't invent a conspiracy
theory to put back his halo.
Or yours.
- Major.
- FARRIS: Sir.
PERRY: So.
I logged into your Dropbox to find copy.
There's copy all right.
But nothing about football.
Nothing about the friends
of the Metropolis Library,
just the goddamn Gotham Bat thing
I told you not to pursue.
If the police won't help,
the press has to do the right thing.
You don't get to decide
what the right thing is.
When the Planet was founded,
it stood for something, Perry.
And so could you if it was 1938,
but it's not 1938.
WPA ain't hiring no more.
Apples don't cost a nickel.
Not in here, not out there.
You drop this thing!
Nobody cares about Clark Kent
taking on the Batman.
JON STEWART: So apparently Superman
doesn't want us to think of him
as American anymore.
And really, why would we?
Aside from the red and blue costume.
And, I don't know, the fact that he has
one-third of the USA's
initials on his chest.
I assume the only reason he's not wearing
the Declaration of
Independence as a cape is...
He thinks it's too on-the-nose.
- MANAGER: What is going on back here?
- No.
Guys, come on. Let's go.
Get yourselves together and get out there.
Get those glasses on those trays.
We got thirsty people out there.
I wonder, would you excuse us?
- There's something I'd like to show you.
- I'm sorry.
Now some scholars insist
that it never happened...
But I believe it's the action
perfectly in keeping with a king
who was also a psychopathic killer.
For me, it's the culmination
of 40 years curating.
And I can't believe it,
but I've finally got it here.
It's the Sword of Alexander.
It's the blade that cut the Gordian knot.
It's a triumph.
DIANA: Yes.
JAMES HARMON: Enjoy.
DIANA: Thank you.
It's a fake.
The real one was sold
in '98 on the black market.
And now it hangs...
Over the bed of the Sultan of Hajar.
Excuse me.
Excuse me, miss.
The other night you took something
that doesn't belong to you.
Stealing's not polite.
Is it stealing if you steal
from another thief?
Who are you?
Someone interested
in the same man you are.
Is that right?
I believe Mr. Luthor has a photograph
that belongs to me.
Did you get it?
As it happens, no, I didn't.
The data you copied has
military-grade encryption.
You know, I bet with that dress,
9 out of 10 men will let you
get away with anything.
But you're the 10th?
I'm guessing I'm the first
to see through that
babe-in-the-woods act.
You don't know me,
but I've known a few women like you.
I don't think you've ever
known a woman like me.
You know, it's true what
they say about little boys.
Born with no natural
inclination to share.
I didn't steal your drive. I borrowed it.
You'll find it in the glove
compartment of your car.
Mr. Wayne.
(BEEPING)
(TYPING)
Did you get it?
The rock?
Yeah, we got it.
(GUN COCKS)
I'm sorry.
(GRUNTS)
Get down! Get down now!
No!
(ALL GRUNTING)
(GROANING)
(GRUNTING CONTINUES)
(GROANS)
(GASPS)
(RUMBLING)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(GRUNTS)
She was my world.
And you took her from me.
(SCREAMS)
- (GASPS)
- THE FLASH: Bruce!
Bruce! Listen to me now!
It's Lois!
It's Lois Lane!
She's the key!
Am I too soon?
(GRUNTS IN ANNOYANCE)
I'm too soon!
You're right about him!
You've always been right about him!
Fear him! Fear him!
Find us, Bruce!
You have to find us!
(GASPS)
BRUCE: The White Portuguese is not a man.
It's a ship.
Master Wayne, since the age of seven
you have been to the art of deception
as Mozart to the harpsichord.
But you've never been
too hot at lying to me.
The White Portuguese is not
carrying a dirty bomb.
What is it carrying?
It's a weapon.
It's a rock.
A mineral capable of weakening
Kryptonian cells.
The first sample big enough
to mean something
turned up in the Indian Ocean
three months ago.
It is now aboard the White Portuguese
being delivered to Lex Luthor.
Who I am going to steal it from.
To keep it out of Luthor's hands.
To destroy it.
No.
You're gonna go to war?
That son of a bitch brought
the war to us two years ago.
Jesus, Alfred. Count the dead.
Thousands of people.
What's next? Millions?
He has the power to wipe out
the entire human race,
and if we believe there's even
a 1 % chance that he is our enemy,
we have to take it
as an absolute certainty.
And we have to destroy him.
But he is not our enemy.
Not today.
20 years in Gotham, Alfred.
We've seen what promises are worth.
How many good guys are left.
How many stayed that way.
14 hours.
My name is Clark Kent.
I'm from the Daily Planet.
I'm trying to find out
what happened to an inmate,
a Santos.
I can't give out that information.
Mommy!
Mrs. Santos?
May I ask you a few questions?
He wasn't my husband.
But I know what he did.
But he was a father. He was that, too.
They took him out of Gotham Central.
They moved him to Metropolis.
But inside they know.
They know the mark all over.
Guards don't care.
Bat's the judge.
One man decides who lives.
- How is that justice?
- Talk to me.
- Help me change it.
- With what? Your pen?
A man like that, words don't stop him.
You know stops him? A fist.
(BABY CRYING)
PERRY: Kent, I want
to talk to you.
Kent!
Where does he go?
Where does he go, Jenny?
I don't... I don't know.
Clicks his heels three times,
goes back to Kansas, I suppose.
Son of a...
(SHIP HORN BLOWING)
(MAN YELLING)
WORKER: Turn it! Turn it!
(BEEPING)
Move out!
(TIRES SCREECHING)
Go, go, go, go!
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
No!
(ENGINE REVVING)
(GRUNTS)
(TRAIN HORN BLARING)
(GUNFIRE)
- (YELLS)
- (TIRES SCREECHING)
- (GUNFIRE CONTINUES)
- (BEEPING)
(HORN BLARING)
Where is he?
(ENGINE REVVING)
(BEEPING)
(TIRES SCREECHING)
- (CAR ALARM BLARING)
- (BATMAN BREATHES HEAVILY)
(FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING)
(CAR ALARM STOPS)
Next time they shine
your light in the sky,
don't go to it.
The Bat is dead. Bury it.
Consider this mercy.
BRUCE: Tell me.
Do you bleed?
You will.
(ENGINE REVVING)
(BEEPING)
I don't have a halo over me,
Mr. Secretary.
I went into the desert, people died.
It keeps me awake. It should.
If you think that Superman is a murderer,
then throw it away.
But I don't believe you think that.
FINCH: How do we determine
what's good?
In a democracy, good is a conversation,
- not a unilateral decision.
- (CAMERAS CLICKING)
So I urge Superman to come
to this Hill of the People tomorrow
to see those who have suffered.
The world needs to know
what happened in that desert.
And to know what he stands for.
How far will he take his power?
Does he act by our will or by his own?
MARTHA: People hate
what they don't understand.
But they see what you do,
and they know who you are.
You're not a killer, a threat.
I never wanted this world to have you.
(SIGHS)
Be their hero, Clark. Be their monument.
Be their angel.
Be anything they need you to be.
Or be none of it.
You don't owe this world a thing.
You never did.
DRIVER: This is De Niros.
Transfer available to Kane Avenue.
Please, mind your step.
(DOORS HISSING)
KAHINA:
I have to speak to the senator today.
RECEPTIONIST:
You cannot see the senator today.
KAHINA: I need to speak to her
before the hearing.
Do you understand how important this is?
RECEPTIONIST:
I cannot let you see the senator.
KAHINA: Please, I need to speak to her.
Please, madam. I beg of you!
Please don't do this!
This is so important!
- OFFICER: Come with me.
- Don't touch me!
- Please!
- I'm sorry. She wouldn't leave.
I didn't tell you the truth.
C.I. thinks the desert was a setup.
Somebody wanted Superman to look guilty.
(SIGHS) The bullet?
The metal was developed
by a private company.
What company?
LexCorp.
Lex Luthor?
He also had private security contractors
at the desert compound.
Go on record.
Not a chance. It's classified.
I happen to like my job.
It doesn't make sense.
You said that the ambush was
arranged to frame Superman,
but how could they know
that he'd show up in the... (GASPS)
In the middle of the desert. Thank you.
- (INDISTINCT CHATTER)
- (BEEPING)
The Senate hearing is expected
to get underway any minute now.
And of course the big
unknown in all of this is
will Superman show up?
That is what they're really
waiting to see.
Mr. Keefe. Mr. Keefe.
Soledad O'Brien, In the Moment.
Quick question for you.
You're heading in
to meet with the senators.
What will you tell them?
KEEFE: I've come here
to tell them to wake up.
This is flesh and blood.
He has delivered a war here.
And this...
This is what war looks like.
I have nothing.
There are plenty of people,
sir, who would say he's their hero.
He is not a hero.
Grace, can you get Greg up here, please?
Right now.
An anonymous source can verify everything
I told you about what
happened in Nairomi.
- An anonymous source?
- Run it.
Luthor engineered the desert.
It was an ambush for Superman.
Trust your reporter. Think Watergate.
Yeah, and you need to think litigate.
If you're wrong, Luthor will
sue the paper out of existence.
You need proof.
No. It needs to run now.
Before the hearing.
If Superman knows,
it might change what he says.
I am not going to risk the paper
so that you can pass notes in class
to the man that rescued you.
McGRAW: He paid her?
(STUTTERS) Not only paid her.
He threatened her.
Gave her a script to learn.
Her parents are alive back home.
But the girl's got a conscience.
He's been using the committee
as his puppet theater.
Senator!
Hi, you.
Don't go anywhere. I want to talk to you.
Uh, you know what?
Mercy, you go in and make sure
no one takes my seat.
So what you been up to?
I'm just here to tell my story.
That I was willing to finance
a Kryptonian deterrent,
but a certain junior senator from Kentucky
decided to block it.
Yes, the chair of the committee
on Superman is soft on security.
Greg, why hasn't he been
getting our checks?
He is, Mr. Wayne.
He gets a check from
the Victims Fund every month.
GREG: He returns them.
DANA BASH: ...who lost both his legs
in those horrific events in Metropolis
that happened two years ago.
BRUCE: Jesus.
Why haven't I seen this?
GREG: I'm sorry.
I'll get to the bottom of it.
BASH: And there he is. Superman is here.
He is actually
at the United States Capitol.
This is really a historic moment.
Now we expect that Superman will give
some kind of a statement to the Senate,
to the American people,
and, of course, to the world.
He's here. He came.
- He's above the Capitol.
- Ah.
You are gonna be on the
hot seat in there, Junebug.
I grew up on a farm.
I know how to wrestle a pig.
Do you know the oldest lie
in America, Senator?
It's that power can be innocent.
Good luck.
(TRAIN HORN BLOWING)
(SCREAMING)
- Oh, miss...
- (PEOPLE CLAMORING)
Rudy, she's good to go.
(PEOPLE CHEERING)
Get out!
- Get out! Get out!
- Superman! Superman!
GREG: Another one came
this morning, Mr. Wayne.
- (PEOPLE MURMURING)
- (DOOR OPENS)
Let me say at the outset
that I'm grateful to our witness
for coming before us today.
This is how a democracy works.
We talk to each other.
We act by the consent
of the governed, sir.
I have sat here before
to say that shadow interventions
will not be tolerated by this committee.
Neither will lies.
Because today is a day for truth.
Because only by speaking...
Only by working together can we...
(STAMMERS) Can we...
Can we create a free, and a...
(SHUDDERING)
(PEOPLE SCREAMING)
(GASPS)
REPORTER: Oh, my God!
- (WOMAN SHRIEKS)
- (HORSE NEIGHS)
(PEOPLE CONTINUE SCREAMING)
(WOMAN SOBBING)
REPORTER: We're back
at the nation's Capitol,
where something is happening.
(PAPER RUSTLING)
(CHILD SCREAMS)
(SIRENS WAILING)
LOIS: Excuse me.
Excuse me, officer.
Member of the press.
Can you let me in, please?
PARAMEDIC: Breathe slowly and deeply.
You're gonna be fine.
Thank you.
I'm gonna need a little room to work.
Ma'am, it appears you've
suffered a head injury.
I'm gonna need you
to follow my light with your eyes.
(CAMERAS CLICKING)
Master Wayne.
Mr. Wayne!
REPORTER: ...in the Senate hearing room
where Superman was testifying.
This is a catastrophic
situation at our nation's Capitol.
We don't have exact numbers yet,
but I can tell you that
more than a dozen people
have died in this explosion.
First responders are at the scene.
They are still bringing victims out.
Now initially, Superman was helping
bring victims out after the blast,
but he seems to have disappeared...
- ...raising questions.
- (EXHALES)
Carrie Birmingham,
reporting live from the nation's capital.
REPORTER 2: Capitol police are now
confirming that the blast was caused
by an explosive device
inside the hearing room.
(SIRENS BLARING)
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
OFFICER: Run that one more time for me.
- Can you enhance that?
- There you go, sir.
REPORTER ON TV:
Capitol police are confirming to CNN
that the suspected bomber is
Wallace Vernon Keefe. Now these sources...
Clark, it's me again. Can you...
...could have gotten
the explosive device into the hearing
by concealing them inside his wheelchair.
As for Superman, he was in the room,
but obviously failed to stop him.
I didn't see it, Lo.
I was standing right there
and I didn't see it.
Clark, there are people behind this.
I'm afraid I didn't see it
because I wasn't looking.
All this time,
I've been living my life
the way my father saw it.
Righting wrongs for a ghost.
Thinking I'm here to do good.
Superman was never real.
Just the dream of a farmer from Kansas.
That farmer's dream
is all some people have.
It's all that gives them hope.
This means something.
It did on my world.
My world doesn't exist anymore.
(SONIC BOOM)
(SIGHS)
(DISTORTED VOICES)
KRYPTONIAN SHIP VOICE: Welcome.
Analysis reveals ship
operating at 37% efficiency.
Would you like to assume command?
Yes, I would.
Yes, I would. (CLEARS THROAT)
Very well. Let's begin.
The Kryptonian archive contains knowledge
from 100,000 different worlds.
Good. Teach me.
(GRUNTING)
(CONTINUES GRUNTING)
(YELLS)
(BRUCE CONTINUES GRUNTING)
KRYPTONIAN SHIP VOICE: Alexander Luthor,
your security override has been accepted.
Genesis Chamber ready
to analyze genetic sample.
Acknowledging presence
of genetic material.
Analyzing.
I've identified the host as
General Zod of Kandor.
(KNIFE OPENING)
(GROANS)
(BLOOD DRIPPING)
Acknowledging presence
of foreign genetic material.
Analyzing.
You flew too close to the sun.
Now look at you.
Advising. Action forbidden.
It has been decreed
by the Council of Krypton
that none will ever again
give life to a deformity
so hateful to sight and memory.
The desecration without name.
And where is the Council of Krypton?
Destroyed, sir.
Then proceed.
Very well.
Preparing chrysalis
and commencing metamorphosis.
JENNY: "And so we are left to wonder
"if Superman was aware of
the threat and did nothing,
"was he then complicit
in the Capitol tragedy?"
Still no Kent?
JENNY: "His disappearance
raises questions."
No.
DANA BASH: There are still so many
unanswered questions.
Chief among them,
whether Superman was involved
in the planning of this attack.
I mean, here's an individual
who has unlimited power,
yet did nothing to stop the bomber
just a few feet away from him.
It just doesn't add up for investigators.
CROWD: (CHANTING ON TV)
Burn him, burn him, burn him.
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
For 20 American, he didn't see you.
Same for me.
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
REPORTER: Now one FBI official
familiar with this case
told me they found quote,
"A jackpot of bomb-making materials
inside Keefe's apartment."
What they need to determine now is
whether he had any help in the planning
and execution of the bombing.
And they haven't ruled out the idea
that Superman was a co-conspirator.
Now, my sources are telling me
they are getting a barrage of anonymous
and credible tips
with all roads in this investigation
leading to the Kryptonian visitor.
(TAPPING)
All right, Lois. You gotta go.
He didn't know he was gonna die.
He just bought groceries.
The wheelchair and
the bullet from the desert
were made from the same metal.
I know. The desert. The hearing.
Everywhere Superman goes,
Luthor wants death.
JENET: But, Luthor goes
through all of that trouble...
Creates a bomb out of a wheelchair,
and then alters it to reduce the blast?
What do you mean?
The inside of the chair
was lined with lead.
You couldn't stop it.
(SIGHS) You couldn't see it.
Something, isn't it?
We men of Kansas live on a pancake,
so we come to the mountains.
All downhill from here,
down to the floodplain.
Farm at the bottom of the world.
I remember one season the water came bad.
I couldn't have been 12.
Dad had out the shovels
and we went at it all night.
(CHUCKLES)
We worked till, I think, I fainted.
But we managed to stop the water.
We saved the farm.
Your grandma baked me a cake.
Said I was a hero.
Later that day we found out
we blocked the water all right.
We sent it upstream.
The whole Lang farm washed away.
While I ate my hero cake,
their horses were drowning.
I used to hear them wailing in my sleep.
Did the nightmares ever stop?
Yeah.
When I met your mother.
She gave me faith that
there's good in this world.
She was my world.
I miss you, son.
I miss you too, Dad.
ALFRED: You know you can't win this.
It's suicide.
I'm older now than my father ever was.
This may be the only thing
I do that matters.
20 years of fighting criminals
amounts to nothing?
Criminals are like weeds, Alfred.
Pull one up, another grows in its place.
This is about the future of the world.
This is my legacy.
My father sat me down right here.
Told me what Wayne Manor was built on.
Railroads, real estates, and oil.
The first generation made their fortune
trading with the French.
Pelts and skins.
They were hunters.
So falls the house of Wayne.
NANCY GRACE: We gotta wait for more
evidence, but the question still remains,
where is he?
If Superman was not involved,
if he's got nothing to hide,
then why hasn't he been seen
since the day of this tragedy?
MAN ON TV: You can't point a finger and...
I'm not pointing anything, Warren.
Look. Ten fingers, see?
MAN: If there is going to be a criminal...
(BOTTLES RATTLING)
(SIGHS)
(ENGINE STARTS)
- (ENGINE REVS)
- (GASPS)
- (WHIMPERS)
- (TIRES SCREECH)
(SCREAMING)
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
(RUMBLING)
The night is here.
Excuse me.
Don't I know...
(SCREAMING)
(TIRES SCREECHING)
Plain Lo in the morning. Lola in slacks.
(SIGHS)
Lois Lane.
(SNIFFLES)
Mmm. Come see the view.
Um... (SNIFFLES) Mmm-mmm.
Now the secret to the height
is the building material.
It's light metals
which sway a bit in the wind.
Hmm.
And you know something
about LexCorp metals,
don't you, Miss Lane?
I've proven what you've done.
Wow, you're feisty.
Unfortunately, that will blow away.
Like sand in the desert.
You're psychotic.
That is a three-syllable word
for any thought too big for little minds.
Hmm. Next category: circles.
Round and round
and round they go to find Superman.
(GRUNTS) Wrong category, boy.
No, no, triangles.
Yes, Euclid's triangle inequality.
The shortest distance
between any two points
is a straight path.
And I believe
the straightest path to Superman
is a pretty little road...
(SNIFFS) Mmm. Called Lois Lane.
(GASPS)
(SCREAMING)
(GASPING)
You came back.
Boy, do we have problems up here!
(CLEARS THROAT)
(TICKING)
(STAMMERS)
The problem of... Of evil in the world.
Uh, the problem of absolute virtue.
I'll take you in without breaking you.
Which is more than you deserve.
The problem of you
on top of everything else.
You above all.
Ah, because that's what God is.
Horus. Apollo. Jehovah. Kal-EI.
Clark Joseph Kent.
See, what we call God
depends upon our tribe, Clark-Joe.
Because God is tribal. God takes sides.
No man in the sky intervened
when I was a boy
to deliver me from
Daddy's fist and abominations. Mmm.
I figured out way back,
if God is all-powerful,
he cannot be all-good.
And if he is all-good,
then he cannot be all-powerful.
And neither can you be.
They need to see the fraud you are.
With their eyes.
The blood on your hands.
What have you done?
Hmm. And tonight, they will.
Yes. Because you, my friend,
have a date. Hmm.
Across the bay.
Ripe fruit, his hate. Two years growing.
But it did not take much
to push him over, actually.
Little red notes, big bang.
You let your family die!
And now you will fly to him.
And you will battle him.
To the death.
Black and blue. Fight Night!
The greatest gladiator match
in the history of the world.
- God versus man.
- (THUNDER RUMBLES)
Day versus night.
Son of Krypton versus Bat of Gotham.
You think I'll fight him for you?
Hmm, yes, I do.
I think you will fight-fight-fight
for that special lady in your life.
She's safe on the ground. How about you?
Close, but I am not talking about Lois.
No.
Every boy's special lady is his mother.
(GASPS)
Martha, Martha, Martha.
Hmm.
Why, the mother of a flying demon
must be a witch.
The punishment for witches, what is that?
That's right. Death by fire.
Mmm. (CHUCKLES)
(BREATHING HEAVILY) Where is she?
I don't know!
I would not let them tell me!
Uh-uh-uh! If you kill me, Martha dies.
And if you fly away, mmm,
Martha also dies.
But if you kill the Bat...
Martha lives.
There we go. There we go. Hmm.
And now God bends to my will.
(HELICOPTER APPROACHING)
Ooh, now the cameras
are waiting at your ship.
For the world to see
the holes in the holy.
Yes, the Almighty comes clean
about how dirty he is when it counts.
To save Martha,
bring me the head of the Bat.
Ah.
Mother of God, would you look at the time?
When you came here, you had an hour.
Now it's less.
(TICKING)
ANDERSON COOPER:
Brooke Baldwin is on the scene.
Brooke, you're live on the air.
What are you seeing?
There's something happening at the ship.
It's sending massive power surges.
ERIKA ERICKSON:
Police helicopters surrounding the area.
They've created a barricade
around this containment center.
And we're trying to get
a little bit closer here
to find out what's going on.
It is absolute chaos.
You can see that lightning,
those surges of electricity.
They seem to be getting
stronger by the minute.
Daily Planet.
Lois.
I have to go to Gotham
to convince him to help me.
Who?
Or he has to die.
Clark.
No one stays good in this world.
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
ERICKSON: But as of right now, much of
the city remains in the dark tonight.
Much chaos.
Much confusing happening
on the streets of Metropolis tonight.
Those helicopters are still
surrounding the area.
I don't know if you can
still see those bolts of lightning...
(BEEPS)
(COMPUTER BEEPS)
2400 hours and 2 minutes.
Subject declining rapidly.
All procedural interventions have failed.
- Outcome will be death.
- (SWITCHES TAPE RECORDER OFF)
(YELLS)
Dr. Silas Stone
suspending all clinical protocol.
US Gov, object 6-19-82
is successfully activated.
(WHIMPERING)
(SCREAMING)
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
LOIS: I need a chopper to Gotham.
Call the heliport.
Chopper? We can barely afford a bicycle.
You wanna chase a story? Go to the ship.
Superman's probably there already.
Perry, it's not for a story.
Jenny, get her a chopper to Gotham.
And forget the heliport.
Put it on the goddamn roof.
On the roof, Lois!
Where are we headed?
There!
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
Well, here I am.
Bruce. Please.
I was wrong. You have to listen to me.
Lex wants us to...
(HIGH-PITCHED RINGING)
(GROANING)
You don't understand.
There's no time!
I understand.
(GROANING)
(GRUNTS)
(PANTING)
(GROANS)
Stay down!
If I wanted it, you'd be dead already.
(GRUNTS)
(WHIRRS)
(CHOKING)
Breathe it in.
That's fear.
You're not brave.
(GRUNTS)
Men are brave.
(BOTH GRUNTING)
(GROANS)
(GASPS)
(GRUNTS)
(GROANING)
(CHOKES)
(GRUNTING)
(GROANING)
(BOTH GRUNTING)
(YELLS)
(GROANING)
(CHOKING)
(GRUNTING)
(GROANS)
I bet your parents taught you
that you mean something.
That you're here for a reason.
My parents taught me a different lesson,
- (GRUNTING)
- dying in the gutter
for no reason at all.
(GROANS)
(SCREAMS)
(YELLS)
(CONTINUES GROANING)
They taught me the world only makes sense
if you force it to.
(HELICOPTER APPROACHING)
(GROANS)
You were never a God.
You were never even a man.
(STRAINING)
You're letting him kill Martha.
(CHOKING)
What does that mean?
Why did you say that name?
Find him.
Save
Martha.
THOMAS: Martha.
(PEARLS CLATTERING)
(SCREAMING INAUDIBLY)
Martha.
Why did you say that name?
(FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING)
Martha! Why did you say that name?
Clark! Stop!
Please! Stop!
Why did you say that name?
It's his mother's name!
It's his mother's name. (PANTING)
(GRUNTS)
- (SIRENS WAILING)
- ERICKSON: We're not getting any answers.
We're still right outside
the containment center.
A dangerous situation.
Military and police personnel
surrounding the area.
(MARTHA PANTING)
CLARK: Luthor.
He wanted your life for hers.
She's losing time.
The scout ship seems to be
drawing power from the city.
It's got to be Lex.
They need you at that ship. I'll find her.
- My mother needs me.
- Wait.
I'll make you a promise.
Martha won't die tonight.
ALFRED: Master Wayne.
Alfred.
Uh, I'm sorry for listening in,
but I've tracked the Russian's phone
to a warehouse near the port.
You're locked onto it.
I don't deserve you, Alfred.
No, sir. You don't.
KNYAZEV: I'm afraid this is goodbye.
And every time we say goodbye,
you die a little.
(BAT PLANE APPROACHING)
MAN 1: Take it down.
MAN 2: Go! Go!
You have to take it, Alfred.
Ah, right.
Commencing drone mode.
Thermal imaging is showing me
two dozen hostiles on the third floor.
Why don't I drop you off on the second?
(BAT PLANE APPROACHING)
(DOOR SLAMS)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(PANICKED SHOUTING)
- (BEEPING)
- (GASPS)
(GROANING)
(YELLS)
(GROANS)
(SCREAMING)
(GROANING)
(GASPS)
(SCREAMS)
- (MAN YELLING)
- (GUN FIRING)
(SCREAMS)
(ALL GRUNTING)
(GRUNTING)
(GROANS)
(SCREAMS)
(GROANING)
(WHIMPERING)
Drop it.
I said drop it!
I'll kill her.
Believe me, I'll do it.
I believe you.
(SIGHS)
It's okay. I'm a friend of your son's.
(PANTING) I figured.
The cape.
(TICKING)
- (DINGS)
- (EXPLOSIONS)
(GASPS)
"Late, late," says the White Rabbit.
KRYPTONIAN SHIP VOICE:
Forty seconds to animation.
Right, wabbit?
Hmm. Out of tricks, out of time.
And one Bat head short.
KRYPTONIAN SHIP VOICE:
Thirty seconds to animation.
- (PHONE RINGS)
- Ah. That'll be the cook. Excuse me.
Uh, Gotham Roast. Well done.
Hello. Break the bad news.
BRUCE: I'd rather do
the breaking in person.
KRYPTONIAN SHIP VOICE:
Twenty seconds to animation.
You've lost.
I don't know how to lose.
- You'll learn.
- (CHUCKLES)
I'll learn.
I don't hate the sinner.
- I hate the sin.
- 10 seconds to animation.
And yours, my friend, is existing.
I cannot let you win.
I gave the Bat a fighting chance to do it,
but he was not strong enough.
So, if man won't kill God...
KRYPTONIAN SHIP VOICE: ...two, one.
...the devil will do it!
(MACHINE WHIRRING)
(ELECTRICITY CRACKLING)
(ELECTRICITY CONTINUES CRACKLING)
- (GASPS)
- (PEOPLE EXCLAIMING)
JENNY: Perry!
PERRY: All right. Stay calm, everybody!
We're getting reports
there are total blackouts
in the north and to
the northwest of the city.
Federal authorities
are trying to determine
if this is part of
a larger terrorist attack.
Ancient Kryptonian deformity.
Hmm. Blood of my blood.
(GROWLING)
Born to destroy you.
Your Doomsday.
(GROWLING CONTINUES)
(ROARING)
Now God is good as dead.
Oh!
(ROARING CONTINUES)
(GRUNTING)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(ELECTRICITY CRACKLING)
(CLARK GROANING)
(PANTING)
(GROWLING)
(HELICOPTER APPROACHING)
(GRUNTING)
(SNARLING)
(GROANING)
(CLARK GRUNTING)
(HELICOPTER APPROACHING)
(GROWLING)
POTUS joining.
SWANWICK: Mr. President.
PRESIDENT: What the hell is it, Calvin?
COOPER: These are live images from the top
of the LexCorp tower
in downtown Metropolis.
Military aircraft are on the scene.
(MARTHA PANTING)
(GASPS)
- Are you hurt, ma'am?
- I'm okay.
Good. You're gonna be all right, okay?
COOPER: This thing emerged
from the Kryptonian crash site
just moments ago.
Thankfully though, the work day is over
in the downtown core.
It's nearly empty.
Now military aircraft.
Those are Apache helicopters.
They have now just arrived.
The images that...
(DOOMSDAY ROARING)
We've, uh... We just lost
connection with Metropolis 8 News.
Now, it's not clear what just happened.
What's happening there, Alfred?
(EXHALES)
How best to describe it?
ANNOUNCER: Metropolis airspace
has been closed briefly.
FLIGHT ATTENDANT: Excuse me?
We kindly ask that you stay in your seats.
Excuse me?
Miss Prince?
(DOOMSDAY ROARING)
(GRUNTING)
Sir. Look, they've cleared the city.
Looks like he's taking it into space.
We can go
straight to Key Red, Mr. President.
Not yet. Are you crazy?
They're high enough that we can nuke 'em
with no casualties, sir.
One casualty, Mr. President. Superman.
(PRESIDENT SIGHS)
PRESIDENT: God have mercy on us all.
(SIGHS IN RELIEF)
(ALARM BLARING)
- Key is hot.
CHAIRMAN OF JOINT CHIEFS:
Red birds are armed to deploy, sir.
PRESIDENT: Fire at will.
Three, two, one...
(DOOMSDAY GRUNTS)
(DOOMSDAY ROARING)
Oh, God.
Projectile 1. Impact.
Stryker's Island, east of Metropolis.
That's uninhabited.
Projectile 2...
No apparent reentry.
PRESIDENT: Projectile 2?
Superman, Mr. President.
Projectile 2 was Superman.
SIGNALS OFFICER: Sir.
It's moving.
(DOOMSDAY GROWLING)
(ELECTRICITY CRACKLING)
(DOOMSDAY ROARING)
SWANWICK:
The shockwaves are getting stronger.
Every time we hit it,
we make it more powerful.
We can't attack.
PRESIDENT: What are you saying, Calvin?
I'm saying it's unkillable.
- (SIGHS)
- (BEEPING)
(RAPID BEEPING)
(GROWLS)
(GROANS)
Master Wayne, are you receiving me?
BRUCE: Alfred.
It's Kryptonian.
Only Kryptonite weapons can kill it.
They might. If you had any left.
I got one round left.
The spear. Alfred, the spear.
It's pure Kryptonite.
It's back in Gotham.
If I can penetrate the skin,
the spear will kill it.
It would in theory.
I've gotta get it to chase me
back to the city.
- Back to the Kryptonite.
- (ENGINE REVVING)
(GRUNTING)
(DOOMSDAY GROWLING)
(GROANING)
(PANTING)
(DOOMSDAY ROARING)
Oh, shit.
(GRUNTS)
(PANTING)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(GROANS)
Why did you bring him back to the city?
BRUCE: The port is abandoned.
There's a weapon here that can kill it.
Did you find the spear?
I've been a little busy.
This thing, this creature,
seems to feed on energy.
CLARK: This thing is from another world.
My world.
I've killed things
from other worlds before.
Is she with you?
I thought she was with you.
(DOOMSDAY ROARING)
(ELECTRICITY CRACKLING)
(SIRENS WAILING)
(GASPING)
(PANTING)
(DOOMSDAY GROWLS)
(DIANA YELLING)
(GRUNTS)
(DIANA GRUNTING)
(ROARING)
(CLARK GRUNTING)
(GROANING)
(YELLS)
(MUFFLED SCREAMS)
(DOOMSDAY GROWLING)
(YELLING)
(BANGING)
(MUFFLED SCREAMS)
(COUGHING)
(PANTING)
(GROWLING)
(BRUCE GRUNTS)
(BRUCE GROANING)
(DOOMSDAY ROARING)
(PANTING)
Clark!
(WHIMPERING)
(GRUNTS)
- (COUGHS)
- Clark!
Clark! Are you all right?
(DIANA GRUNTING)
(CHUCKLES)
(YELLS)
(GRUNTS)
(ELECTRICITY CRACKLING)
(DIANA SCREAMS)
(ROARING)
(BOTH PANTING)
I love you.
No. No, Clark, you can't.
This is my world.
No, Clark, don't.
You are my world.
No.
Please. Clark!
(DOOMSDAY GROWLING)
(GRUNTING)
(YELLING)
(PANTING)
(YELLS)
(GROANS LOUDLY)
(GROANING)
(DOOMSDAY ROARING)
(GRUNTING)
(GROANING)
(CLARK YELLING)
(PANTING)
(CRYING)
(GROWLING)
(ELECTRIC RAZOR WHIRRING)
(SPEAKING INAUDIBLY)
(SNIFFLES)
(KNOCKING ON DOOR)
Hi.
Clark had this sent here,
so he could surprise you.
(BAGPIPES PLAYING)
(JET ENGINE ROARING)
FATHER LEONE: "The dead shall live.
"My slain shall rise again.
"Awake and sing, ye that dwell in dust.
"For thy dew is like the dew of morning.
"And the earth
shall give birth to her dead."
MARTHA: Ah, I need a ride
back to the house.
I forgot my checkbook
to pay the funeral director.
They said it's all taken care of.
By whom?
Anonymous donor.
All those circuses back east
burying an empty box.
They don't know how to honor him,
except as a soldier.
I've failed him in life.
I won't fail him in death.
Help me find the others like you.
Perhaps they don't want to be found.
They will. And they'll fight.
We have to stand together.
(SIGHS)
100 years ago, I walked away from mankind.
From a century of horrors.
Man made a world where
standing together is impossible.
Men are still good.
BRUCE: We fight. We kill.
We betray one another.
But we can rebuild.
We can do better.
We will.
We have to.
The others like me.
Why did you say they'll have to fight?
Just a feeling.
(CELL DOOR OPENS)
Prisoner A-C-23-19-40.
The warden wants to speak to you,
so stand to your feet.
I'm gonna say this one more time.
The warden wants to speak to you,
so stand to your feet.
SUPERMAX GUARD:
Turn around and face the wall.
Place your forehead against the wall.
Put your hands behind your back,
so that I can come in and restrain you.
(GATE OPENS)
Whatever you do, wherever you go,
I'll be watching you.
Oh...
Look at us.
This is how it all caves in.
Civilization on the Wayne Manor's
out the window.
Mmm?
(SNORTS)
But who would believe me?
(STAMMERING) I...
(STUTTERS) I'm insane.
I'm not even fit to stand trial.
That's right.
We have hospitals that treat
the mentally ill with compassion.
- (SNICKERS)
- But that's not where you're going.
I arranged for you to get transferred
to Arkham Asylum in Gotham.
I still have some friends there.
They're expecting you.
But the bell's already been rung.
And they've heard it.
Out in the dark.
Among the stars. Hmm.
Ding dong, the God is dead.
(BRUCE GRUNTS)
(DOOR BUZZING)
But a bell cannot be unrung!
He's hungry. He's found us.
And he's coming!
Ding, ding, ding, ding, ding,
ding, ding, ding, ding.
Ding, ding, ding, ding, ding.
Ding, ding, ding, ding, ding,
ding, ding, ding, ding.
English - SDH